dovepress.com 2019-11-29

# Dove Medical Press Privacy Policy

**Dove Medical Press Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy ("Policy") sets out the data processing practices carried out through the use of the internet and other electronic communications networks by Dove Medical Press. If you have any requests concerning your personal information or any queries with regard to these practices please contact our [Data Protection Officer](mailto:privacy@dovepress.com?subject=Dove%20Medical%20Press%20Privacy%20Policy). 

This Policy applies to all Dove Medical Press services provided to our customers and visitors to our website. The terms and conditions governing your use of the Dove Medical Press website and associated services are defined in our Terms and Conditions (“Terms and Conditions”). In the event that we change the way in which we collect, process or store your personal data we will update our Policy accordingly and provide you with information regarding these updates.

If Dove Medial Press chooses to offer new and additional services to you as our customer or as a visitor to our website, those additional services will similarly be provided in accordance with this Policy.

**Information collected**

We collect information from visitors to this website through the use of online forms.

If you are a visitor to our website only, and do not complete a registration then by visiting this website, you consent to the collection and use of the following personal data:

  * IP Address
  * Cookies (more details below)
  * Number of visits
  * Geo-location data (City level only)
  * Length of time spent on website 
  * Pages clicked on

We utilise this personal data to communicate with visitors to our website, customise content and improve our website by analysing how visitors use our website. If you do not agree with our Policy, please do not visit this website.

In addition to the above, we collect information automatically about your visit to our website through the use of cookies. A cookie is a small piece of information sent by a web server to a web browser, which enables the server to collect information from the browser. You can find out more about cookies on www.allaboutcookies.org  
We use cookies to identify you when you visit this website and to keep track of your browsing patterns and build up a demographic profile.  
Most browsers will allow you to turn off cookies. If you would like to do this please look at the menu on your browser, or at the instructions on www.allaboutcookies.org

We use the following cookies on our site:

**  Cookie **

| 

**  Data collected by the cookie  **

| 

**  How long this data is kept for       
**

| 

**  Who owns this data **

| 

**  Is this a 1st party or a 3rd party cookie? **  
  
---|---|---|---|---  
  
 adword cookie

| 

 Token

| 

 1 day 

| 

 Dove Medical Press 

| 

 1st party  
  
 dovepressLogin 

| 

 Token 

| 

 30 days 

| 

 Dove Medical Press 

| 

 1st party  
  
 download_XXX 

| 

 Token 

| 

 1 day

| 

 Dove Medical Press 

| 

 1st party   
  
 PHPSESSIONID

| 

 Token 

| 

 For the session 

| 

 Dove Medical Press  

| 

 1st party  
  
 _GA

| 

 Token

| 

 2 years

| 

 Google

| 

 3rd party  
  
 _DC_GTM

| 

 Token 

| 

 1 hour 

| 

 Google

| 

 3rd party   
  
By continuing to use this site you are agreeing to the use of cookies as detailed above.

In addition, we collect personal data from you when you register on our website and complete a registration form. Once registered, via your secure login we similarly collect data about the transactions you undertake through our website. The following is the personal data which we collect from you at the time of registration:

  * Name
  * IP Address 
  * Email
  * City
  * Country
  * Phone Number 
  * Job Title
  * Department 
  * Organisation 
  * Details as to your last log in 
  * CV (if requested)

If you are a Consultant Editor, Editor in Chief or on our Editorial Board then in addition to the aforementioned personal data we shall also request from you the following personal data, which we will then store and process in accordance with our Policy:

  * Photograph 
  * Affiliations 
  * Your professional profile/CV

**Use of personal information**

We process personal information collected via this website for the purposes of:

  * Dealing with your enquiries and requests;
  * Processing your manuscript;
  * Administering payment of the publication processing fee for your manuscript;
  * Providing email alerts to journals you have registered for.
  * Sharing your personal data (email address only) with third parties, such as a marketing agency, to ensure that you are excluded from a mailing list promoting registration to our website. 
  * Providing information to other companies in the Dove Medical Press group for the purposes of allowing us to continue to provide our services to you and for carrying out daily business operations.
  * Complying with a legal obligation, or to respond to a valid legal process e.g. search warrant, court order, subpoena.
  * A proposed sale of our business. We may share your personal data with a prospective buyer in the event that we sell our business or are negotiating a sale. In this instance, prospective buyers will be bound by appropriate confidentiality arrangements.

**Control of your personal information**

In accordance with local and international privacy laws we offer our customers and visitors to our website the following rights and controls over their personal data:

  * You have the right to be informed about the personal data we process about you and you have the right to request access to your personal data;
  * You have the right to request that Dove Medial Press amend or update the personal data that we hold on you (if that personal data is currently incorrect);
  * You have the right to be forgotten. You may request that we delete your personal data from our systems;
  * You have the right to request that we cease processing your personal data. This restriction may be for a temporary period of time or permanently and may relate to all or part of your personal data;
  * You have the right to object to us processing your personal data;
  * You have the right to object to us utilising your personal data for direct marketing;
  * You have the right to request a copy of the personal data which we hold in relation to you (in electronic form) and the right to send your personal data to a third party;
  * You have the right not to be subjected to automatic decision-making online.

In the event that you wish to exercise any of your aforementioned rights please contact our [Data Protection Officer](mailto:privacy@dovepress.com?subject=Dove%20Medical%20Press%20Privacy%20Policy%20control%20of%20my%20personal%20information).

**Retention of your Personal Data and the Right to be Forgotten**

Dove Medical Press will retain your personal data for as long as required to provide you with our services. During the time that your personal data is held by us it will only be utilised for legitimate business purposes.

In the event that you wish to exercise your Right to be Forgotten we can delete your personal data outright or anonymise your personal data (removing any features that identify the personal data as yours). There are a number of instances in which we may retain your personal data after you have exercised your Right to be Forgotten, and these are as follows:

  * If you are an Author, Editor or Reviewer we shall retain your personal data as it relates to your contribution to an article published on our website. All personal data of yours that we do not require to verify a published article will be deleted in accordance with your right to be forgotten and the personal data we do retain will be for the sole purpose of maintaining the published article and will not be used for the purposes of marketing to you. 
  * An unresolved issue, claim or dispute relating to your log-in. In this case, your personal data will be retained until the issue, claim or dispute is resolved. 
  * Legal, audit, accounting and tax obligations may require us to retain your personal data for a period of time after you exercise your right to be forgotten. 
  * Legitimate internal business use such as security or prevention of fraud. 

**Data Capture Information**

We will send you information according to the preferences you submitted via our online registration form. If you would like to change these preferences at any point you can log in to your secure user account here  then click on "Manage email alerts" to the left. Alternatively you can [email us](mailto:privacy@dovepress.com?subject=Dove%20Medical%20Press%20Privacy%20Policy%20change%20my%20preferences).

**Internal Marketing**

Please note that your information may be used to send you details of our journals and services that we have identified as likely to be of interest to you. This will be in accordance with the preferences that you indicated when you completed the online form.

If, at any point, you would like to opt-out of receiving communications from us please contact our [Data Protection Officer](mailto:privacy@dovepress.com?subject=Dove%20Medical%20Press%20Privacy%20Policy%20opt-out), or you can amend your preferences by logging in to your secure user account here and clicking on "Manage email alerts" in the left column.

**Other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites that are outside our control and are not covered by this Privacy Policy. If you access other sites using the links provided, the operators of these sites may collect information from you that will be used by them in accordance with their privacy policy, which may differ from ours.

**Internet-based transfers**

Given that the internet is a global environment, using it to collect and process personal data necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international basis. This means, for instance, that data you pass to us may be processed outside the European Economic Area, although the data will always be held securely and in line with the requirements of UK data protection legislation. By communicating electronically with us you acknowledge and agree to our processing of personal data in this way.

**Security of Personal Data**

Dove Medical Press is committed to keeping your personal data secure, while we have taken a number of measures to ensure the security of your personal data we remind you that no system is 100% secure.

**Children**

Dove Medical Press' services and website are not directed to children under the age of 13 years. As such we do not intentionally collect personal data from children under the age of 13 years. If you are under the age of 13 years, please do not use register for our services or use our website and do not provide us with your personal data.

Parents, if you are aware that your child under the age of 13 years has provided their personal data to Dove Medical Press please contact our [Data Protection Officer](mailto:privacy@dovepress.com?subject=Dove%20Medical%20Press%20Privacy%20Policy%20child%20under%20the%20age%20of%2013%20years%20provided%20their%20personal%20data).

If we learn that we have collected the personal data of a child under the age of 13 years, we will take reasonable steps to delete the personal data.

**Amendments**

Please note that this Privacy Policy is subject to change from time to time. It was last updated in May 2018.

Updated 25 May 2018
